<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xml:base="https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lincoln Highway Journal</title>
    <link>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>a road trip along the Main Street Across America</description>
    <language>en</language>
      <item>
        <title>Do I have enough food?</title>
        <link>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/</link>
        <description>When you&#39;re a vegan with food allergies, gotta make sure there&#39;s plenty to eat.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been stocking up on food since about May, around the time of graduation. Besides having the usual road trip snacks like trail mix and dried fruit, I&#39;ve also got myself so much food that I&#39;m wondering if it will all fit in the car! Normally, I wouldn&#39;t even &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; to bring this much along, but since I will be traveling for over five weeks, I want to be prepared. When you&#39;re a vegan with food allergies, gotta make sure there&#39;s plenty to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been keeping in mind that there will very most likely be long sections of the drive where nothing will be available for me. My main allergies are soy and peanut, and, well that could be the only option in some areas. This cooler alone holds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two dozen applesauce pouches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;four dozen fruit strips in various flavors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 GoMacro oatmeal chocolate chip bars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18 Nature&#39;s Bakery fig bars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two 4-pack rice ramen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a very large canister of old-fashioned oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dried blueberries and cranberries for the oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;farro and quinoa lunch meal with artichoke and garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;three chili pouches with Beyond crumbles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;several pouches of beans and lentils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two microwave rice pouches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a dozen dried meals from Patagonia and Good to-Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a jar of cinnamon almond butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... this is only the food from the cooler! I&#39;ve also got a huge bag full of veggie straws, cheeze pretzels, orange chips, toasted corn, rice cakes, garlic pretzels, Majool dates, and dried apricots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
  &lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-300w.webp 300w, https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-600w.webp 600w, https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-900w.webp 900w, https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-1200w.webp 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-300w.jpeg 300w, https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-600w.jpeg 600w, https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-900w.jpeg 900w, https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-1200w.jpeg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367542259_18dd82faab_o-300w.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;image &quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;898&quot; alt=&quot;Laird&#39;s Aloha Oatmac and Kenko smoothies&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I wasn&#39;t feeling well one day, and as I lay on the couch I scrolled through Instagram. As usual, there were 87 million ads, but the one for kencko stuck out to me, and before I knew it I was hitting &amp;quot;pay now&amp;quot;. kencko makes powdered smoothie packs, with each individual flavor jammed with fruits and vegetables. Mix with water or milk, and there&#39;s a beverage! I figured they&#39;d work for road trip quick breakfast and that trying them out wouldn&#39;t hurt. Whelp, now I&#39;ve got a subscription and the boxes keep coming every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did a lot of hunting for a vegan powdered milk to bring, and I tasted a few before settling on Laird&#39;s Aloho Oatmac. I&#39;d had their coffee creamer before (which I also bought, but coffee is another post!) and I loved this one so much, I started a scubscription for this one too! But sadly they announced only a few weeks ago they were discontinuing the oatmac. Luckily, I have &lt;em&gt;plenty&lt;/em&gt; in the beverage box. Besides the smoothies, I also plan to use the milk to make overnight oats, when I have a fridge available wherever I end up for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&#39;t to say I &lt;em&gt;won&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; ever stop for food along the way. Just the opposite! I am so much looking forward to hitting diners and restaurants all over the drive; that&#39;s part of the adventure. It&#39;s just the anxiety in me that keeps reminding me of my restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <media:content url="https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/52367651140_19c290b35b_o-300w.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image" />
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator>Reed Piernock</dc:creator>
        <guid>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-18-do-i-have-enough-food/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Documenting the journey</title>
        <link>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-documenting-the-journey/</link>
        <description>It&#39;s only 30 days until I hit the road, and the packing is in full swing.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Part of the journey is not just experiencing adventures, but documenting them. Writing things down or taking photos will remind future-me of everything that happened, and will also provide updates for my friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been years since I&#39;ve journaled regularly, and I&#39;m looking forward to the opportunity to write again. I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leuchtturm1917.us/&quot;&gt;leuchtturm1917&lt;/a&gt; notebooks and have used them the past few years for keeping track of to-dos, or organizing notes from grad school courses. It seemed an obvious choice for my travel journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I bought a smaller notebook to act as an actual travelog, recording dates of travel, miles driven, times of breaks, gas prices, etc. Part of this is the fun of maintaining a register (we&#39;ll see how that changes along the way!) and part is reporting expenses; since I&#39;ll be traveling to a conference, work is sponsoring that part of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minutiae of travel fascinates me, especially over time as roads have been improved and cars have advanced technology. I have a copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/acrosscontinentb00glad&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Across the Continent by the Lincoln Highway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a 1914 account of the cross-country road by Effie Price Gladding. I&#39;m waiting until the trip starts to read it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I further hope to document what it will be like to travel during a pandemic. Although the worst of it is over, covid-19 &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; still a thing, and I&#39;m taking as many safety measures as I can. There is risk involved, for sure, and I&#39;ll do my best to mitigate that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are things you&#39;d like to read on the blog, let me know! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LincHwyJournal&quot;&gt;Find me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-documenting-the-journey/postcard@lincolnhighwayjournal.com&quot;&gt;send an email&lt;/a&gt;. I can&#39;t wait for October to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <media:content url="https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-documenting-the-journey/documenting-300w.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image" />
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator>Reed Piernock</dc:creator>
        <guid>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-documenting-the-journey/</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;m headed for adventure!</title>
        <link>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-i-m-headed-for-adventure/</link>
        <description>I&#39;ve been planning this trip for over three years, and now it&#39;s nearly here.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been planning this trip for over three years, and now it&#39;s nearly here. If you consider daydreaming about doing this, then I&#39;ve really been &amp;quot;planning&amp;quot; for about 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Philadelphia and attended college on the Main Line, an area along Route 30 from Malvern stretching into Philadelphia, named for its association with the old Pennsylvania Railroad and the wealthy communities along it. Most of this section runs right along the Lincoln Highway, and some portions are still named that (while others are named after the old Lancaster Turnpike). When going to school, I often took the SEPTA train into the city, which shares the tracks with Amtrak today. I loved that ride and the road it parallels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/lincoln-highway-brian-a-butko/1100000919?ean=9780811748261&quot;&gt;Brian Butko&#39;s &lt;em&gt;The Lincoln Highway: Pennsylvania Traveler&#39;s Guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; back in the late &#39;90s, and learned that what was Lincoln Highway or Lincoln Ave around my way was not only a route through Pennsylvania, but the whole United States, from Times Square in the east to the Legion of Honor in the west. Fascinated with its history, I dreamed of one day roadtripping the entire length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I entered graduate school in 2019, my wife and I discussed what I wanted to do once I&#39;d completed my degree. After pondering it over, I settled on this adventure: finally driving the entirely of the Lincoln Highway! Many spreadsheets were created, including one with the average high and low temperatures in each state along the route. I choose October for its most appealing temps, and riding in fall meant gorgeous autumn leaves along some parts. I&#39;ve lived among a plethora of spreadsheets, documents, wish lists, to-dos, sticky notes, and maps over the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A session proposal for a tech conference was accepted, and I had to adjust my timing and my route. My journey begins in Arkansas at the conference, then takes me out west, stopping to visit friends along the way. The official Lincoln Highway section of my adventure starts mid-October at the western terminus at the Legion of Honor in San Francisco. I expect to make it to Times Square in New York City in time for my birthday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m excited about this trip, and also looking forward to documenting the travel, the food (so much food!), the weird little things roadside, sweet little local shops, and everything else. One month to go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <media:content url="https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-i-m-headed-for-adventure/9104193151_f9e22e4d4d_o-300w.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image" />
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator>Reed Piernock</dc:creator>
        <guid>https://lincolnhighwayjournal.com/blog/post/2022-09-05-i-m-headed-for-adventure/</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
